export const quizQuestions_8 = {
  questions: [
  {
    question: 'What does component composition refer to in React?',
    choices: [
      'The process of creating new components from existing ones',
      'Using CSS to style components',
      'Creating components that only contain HTML elements',
      'Rendering components in a specific order'
    ],
    correctAnswer: 'The process of creating new components from existing ones'
  },
  {
    question: 'How can you achieve component reusability in React?',
    choices: [
      'By writing complex and specific components',
      'By using global variables inside components',
      'By breaking down UI into smaller, reusable components',
      'By using inline styles for components'
    ],
    correctAnswer: 'By breaking down UI into smaller, reusable components'
  },
  {
    question: 'What are the benefits of component composition in React?',
    choices: [
      'Improved readability and maintainability',
      'Faster performance of the application',
      'Reduction in the number of components used',
      'Increased complexity and rigidity of components'
    ],
    correctAnswer: 'Improved readability and maintainability'
  },
  {
    question: 'What is a higher-order component (HOC) in React?',
    choices: [
      'A component that is rendered at the top of the component tree',
      'A component used for handling HTTP requests',
      'A pattern where a function takes a component and returns a new component',
      'A component that uses state and lifecycle methods'
    ],
    correctAnswer: 'A pattern where a function takes a component and returns a new component'
  },
  {
    question: 'What is the purpose of render props in React component composition?',
    choices: [
      'To define how the component will be rendered',
      'To pass reusable code logic as props to child components',
      'To handle the rendering of a specific prop',
      'To define inline styles for components'
    ],
    correctAnswer: 'To pass reusable code logic as props to child components'
  },
  {
    question: 'How can you share code between React components?',
    choices: [
      'By copying and pasting code between components',
      'By using props drilling',
      'By creating utility functions or custom hooks',
      'By using only class components'
    ],
    correctAnswer: 'By creating utility functions or custom hooks'
  },
  {
    question: 'What does the term "props drilling" refer to in React?',
    choices: [
      'Passing props directly to child components',
      'Passing props through multiple levels of nested components',
      'Passing props from parent to child components',
      'Passing props conditionally based on certain events'
    ],
    correctAnswer: 'Passing props through multiple levels of nested components'
  },
  {
    question: 'Which pattern can be used to share stateful logic between components in React?',
    choices: [
      'Stateful Component Pattern',
      'Singleton Pattern',
      'Container Pattern',
      'React Context API'
    ],
    correctAnswer: 'React Context API'
  },
  {
    question: 'How does React Context API contribute to component reusability?',
    choices: [
      'By reducing the need to pass props through intermediate components',
      'By restricting access to certain components in the application',
      'By automatically rendering components in a specific order',
      'By allowing only class components to access shared state'
    ],
    correctAnswer: 'By reducing the need to pass props through intermediate components'
  },
  {
    question: 'Can you explain the purpose of using compound components in React?',
    choices: [
      'To create components with multiple nested div elements',
      'To encapsulate the structure and logic of a component into multiple smaller components',
      'To use components that have compound properties',
      'To avoid reusing components in React'
    ],
    correctAnswer: 'To encapsulate the structure and logic of a component into multiple smaller components'
    },
  ],
}





